Guide to the Hubert Merrill Sedgwick Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Hubert Merrill Sedgwick papers
1884-1950
MS 1233
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
Correspondence, clippings, memorabilia, photographs, and three books with flyleaf inscriptions relating to Hubert M. Sedgwick's career as a journalist. Included are seventeen letters (1940-1950) from Connie Mack. Two of the books, one by and the other about Mack, contain inscriptions by him and others to Sedgwick. The third is a privately printed book of poetry and aphorisms by Harry Durant, Yale class of 1894. Also in the papers is a statement by William Howard Taft on tuberculosis.
Sedgwick, Hubert M. (Hubert Merrill), 1867-1950
Biographical / Historical
Hubert Merrill Sedgwick, B.A. 1893. Born April 29, 1857, Belchertown, Mass.; died November 11, 1950, New Haven, Conn.
Father, Butler Sedgwick, associated with Clark & Hastings, wholesale and retail meats, Palmer, Mass.; son of Otis and Almira (Converse) Sedgwick. Mother, Minerva Marsha (Hastings) Sedgwick; daughter of Rozel and Phoebe (White) Hastings. Yale relatives include a brother-in-law, Francis H. Todd '95 S.
Worcester Academy; Westfield (Mass.) State Normal School. First colloquy appointment Junior and Senior years.
On staff New Haven Palladium 1894-98; organized sports department New Haven Register 1895, and sports editor 1908-17; executive secretary to Mayor Studley, New Haven, 1907-8, Mayor Rice 1910-17, and Mayor Campner 1917-18; correspondent New York Times, New York Tribune, Boston Transcript, Boston Post, and Chicago Tribune, 1920 until retirement in 1944; contributed to magazines; awarded Gold Key for distinguished service by Connecticut Sports Writers Alliance 1940 and Worcester Academy Shield 1942; secretary athletic committee U.S. Navy Commission on Training Camp Activities 1917-18; field secretary Connecticut Tuberculosis Association 1912-26 (in charge Christmas seal campaigns); president Collectors Club of New Haven 1938-39; secretary Young Men's Institute 1935-41; member New Haven Civic Federation, Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene, Second Company Governor's Foot Guard, and Masonic order; vestryman St. Thomas' Church (Episcopal), New Haven.
Married August 4, 1897, New Haven, Edith Webster, daughter of Theron Alfred and Hattie Emeline (Webster Todd. Children: Ruth (B.A. Vassar 1920; M.A. Yale 1925, Ph.D. 1936); Butler Todd (died in infancy).
Death due to coronary occlusion. Buried in Evergreen Cemetery, New Haven. Survived by wife and daughter.
From the Yale Obituary Record, 1949-51.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, clippings, memorabilia, photographs, and three books with flyleaf inscriptions relating to Hubert M. Sedgwick's career as a journalist. Included are seventeen letters (1940-1950) from Connie Mack. Two of the books, one by and the other about Mack, contain inscriptions by him and others to Sedgwick. The third is a privately printed book of poetry and aphorisms by Harry Durant, Yale class of 1894. Also in the papers is a statement by William Howard Taft on tuberculosis.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Baseball; Tuberculosis; Poems; Journalists; Durant, Harry, 1870-1957; Mack, Connie, 1862-1956; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943; Sedgwick, Hubert M. (Hubert Merrill), 1867-1950; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1894
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1936-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Taft, William Howard. Statement to Tuberculosis Commission, State of Connecticut. Note by Sedgwick, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Hubert M. Sedgwick, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorabilia
    - Clippings, 1940-1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Medal, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gold key, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Biography, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Yale commencement program, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Foot Guard Day: banquet menu, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Relating to: William Lyon Phelps, 1865-1943 [biographical essay, notes], 1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Printed books
    - Durant, Harry. The Happy Age and the Devil's Diary, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lieb, Frederick G. Connie Mack. Grand Old Man of Baseball, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mack, Connie. My 66 Years in the Big Leagues, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)